<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./datadict_v2.xsl"?><data_table id="pht006222.v1" study_id="phs000200.v11" participant_set="3" date_created="Wed Jun 14 08:36:07 2017"><description>Risk Scores (Baseline) - Gail 5 year risk and WHO 10 year probability of fracture/hip fracture</description><variable id="phv00283445.v1"><name>SUBJID</name><description>WHI dbGaP Subject ID</description><type>integer</type></variable><variable id="phv00283446.v1"><name>GAIL5Y</name><description>Gail 5 year risk</description><type>decimal</type><logical_min>0.37</logical_min><logical_max>14.31</logical_max><comment>The Breast Cancer Risk Assessment Tool (i.e., the Gail model) is used to predict risk of invasive breast cancer in women 35 years of age or older. Gail model variables are all from baseline, and include age, ethnicity, age at menarche, age of the mother at the birth of her first live child, number of first-degree relatives with breast cancer, and the number of previous breast biopsy examinations. Because historical information on atypical hyperplasia was not collected in WHI, all women with previous breast biopsy examinations are coded as "unknown" for this variable. Please see the WHI Data Preparation document for more detail and a reference.</comment></variable><variable id="phv00283447.v1"><name>WHOFRAC</name><description>WHO 10-yr probability of fracture (FRAX3)</description><type>decimal</type><logical_min>0.66</logical_min><logical_max>83.91</logical_max><comment>The FRAX (Registered Trademark) tool has been developed by WHO to evaluate fracture risk of patients. It is based on individual patient models that integrate the risks associated with clinical risk factors measured at baseline. WHOFRAC provides the 10-year probability of a major osteoporotic fracture (clinical spine, forearm, hip or shoulder fracture), without taking into account bone mineral density (BMD) at the femoral neck. Please see the WHI Data Preparation document for a reference.</comment></variable><variable id="phv00283448.v1"><name>WHOHIP</name><description>WHO 10-yr probability of hip fracture (FRAX3)</description><type>decimal</type><logical_min>0.02</logical_min><logical_max>80.9</logical_max><comment>The FRAX (Registered Trademark) tool has been developed by WHO to evaluate fracture risk of patients. It is based on individual patient models that integrate the risks associated with clinical risk factors measured at baseline. WHOHIP provides the 10-year probability of a hip fracture, without taking into account bone mineral density (BMD) at the femoral neck. Please see the WHI Data Preparation document for a reference.</comment></variable><variable id="phv00283449.v1"><name>WHOFRACBMD</name><description>WHO 10-yr probability of fracture (FRAX3-uses BMD data)</description><type>decimal</type><logical_min>1.03</logical_min><logical_max>79.28</logical_max><comment>The FRAX (Registered Trademark) tool has been developed by WHO to evaluate fracture risk of patients. It is based on individual patient models that integrate the risks associated with clinical risk factors measured at baseline. WHOFRACBMD provides the 10-year probability of a major osteoporotic fracture (clinical spine, forearm, hip or shoulder fracture), taking into account bone mineral density (BMD) at the femoral neck. Please see the WHI Data Preparation document for a reference.</comment></variable><variable id="phv00283450.v1"><name>WHOHIPBMD</name><description>WHO 10-yr probability of hip fracture (FRAX3-uses BMD data)</description><type>decimal</type><logical_min>0</logical_min><logical_max>61.05</logical_max><comment>The FRAX (Registered Trademark) tool has been developed by WHO to evaluate fracture risk of patients. It is based on individual patient models that integrate the risks associated with clinical risk factors measured at baseline. WHOHIPBMD provides the 10-year probability of a hip fracture, taking into account bone mineral density (BMD) at the femoral neck. Please see the WHI Data Preparation document for a reference.</comment></variable></data_table>
